Which of these statements about files are true?<->
File is a collection of related information
File includes block special files and character special files
File is an abstraction of data stored on HDD
<PASSALL>
Real-time system has ___ and ____ real-time system types<->
hard , soft
<PASSALL>
Allow multiple remote users to run jobs on the computer at once
<->
time sharing systems
<PASSALL>
Which of these statements about address space are true?
<->
Address space is decoupled from the physical memory
Address space is the abstraction that is referenced to the set of addresses a process
<PASSALL>
Which OS can provide many services as print, file, Web, email, ect?
<->
Server OS
<PASSALL>
Server OS serves multiple users at once over a network and allow the users to share ___ and _____ resources
<->
hardware, software
<PASSALL>
____ offers 3 kinds of services: batch, transaction processing, timesharing
<->
Mainframe OS
<PASSALL>
Which of these statements about processes are true?
<->
Associated with each process is set of resources such as executable code, data, stack, CPU registers value, and other information needing to run a program
Process table stores all the information of processes
A program in execution
<PASSALL>
_____ process routine job without interactive user present
<->
batch systems
<PASSALL>
Embedded OS is located in _______
<->
ROM
<PASSALL>
____ runs on systems that have many CPUs (multi-processors, multi-cores, multi-chips)
<->
Multiprocessor OS
<PASSALL>
____ systems are used in time-critical environments where reliability is key and data must be processed within a strict time limit.
<->
Real-time
<PASSALL>
Symbian, Palm, Windows Mobile, Windows CE are ______
<->
Handheld OS
<PASSALL>
_____ serves multiple users at once over a network and allow the users to share hardware and software resources
<->
Server OS
<PASSALL>
_____ supports with dozens of programs started up at the boot time
<->
Multi-programming
<PASSALL>
Handling large numbers of small requests
<->
real-time systems
<PASSALL>
Allow multiple remote users to run jobs on the computer at once
<->
time sharing systems
<PASSALL>
Which of these statements about processes are true?
<->
Process table stores all the information of processes
Associated with each process is set of resources such as executable code, data, stack, CPU registers value, and other information needing to run a program