____ operating systems are typically used for a network platform.
<->
Linux, NetWare, UNIX, Windows
<PASSALL>
The type of system designed to perform one specific function is ____.<->
Embedded
<PASSALL>
The name for the core part of an operating system is____.
<->
kernel
<PASSALL>
___ is a portion of a process that can run independently.
<->thread
<PASSALL>
____ allows a resource to be held by a process as long as it is needed.
<->No preemption
<PASSALL>
___ is the act of allowing only one process to have access to a dedicated resource.
<->Mutual exclusion 
<PASSALL>
Parallel processing is also called ____.
<->multiprocessing 
<PASSALL>
The need for algorithms to resolve conflicts between processors is called process ____.
<->synchronization
<PASSALL>
A ____ of processing must be handled as a unit.
<->critical region 
<PASSALL>
A problem with test-and-set is that when many processes are waiting 
to enter a critical region, ____ could occur because the 
processes gain access in an arbitrary fashion.
<->starvation 
<PASSALL>
____ sets the process’s process control block (PCB) to the blocked state and links it to the 
queue of processes waiting to enter this particular critical region.
<->SIGNAL
<PASSALL>
The two operations identified by Dijkstra to be performed on a semaphore are ____.
<->P and V
<PASSALL>
When using a semaphore, a value of ____ indicates that a critical region is in use.
<->0
<PASSALL>
Operations on semaphore s enforce the concept of ____, which is 
necessary to avoid having two operations attempt to execute at the same time.
<->mutual exclusion
<PASSALL>
____ semaphores are used in the producer and consumer problem.
<->three
<PASSALL>
____ proposed  the readers and writers problem
<->Courtois
<PASSALL>
Each active thread in a process shares the ____ and the resources allocated to its process.
<->data area
<PASSALL>
____ allows for faster turnaround of CPU-bound jobs.
<->Variable time quantum per queue
<PASSALL>
____ jobs are treated like all the others once they are in the system.
<->High-priority
<PASSALL>
Assume jobs A-D arrive in quick succession in the READY queue. 
Using round robin scheduling, the turnaround time for job C is ____.
Arrival time: 0 1 2 3
Job: A B C D
CPU cycle: 8 4 9 5
<->24