When using the clock replacement policy, a page with a reference bit of ____ is replaced.
<->0
<PASSALL>
The need for a memory is ___
<->infinitely fast, nonvolatile, infinitely large
<PASSALL>
The ____ policy is based on the theory that the best 
page to remove is the one that has been in memory the longest.
<->FIFO
<PASSALL>
Fixed partitions are also called ____ partitions.
<->static
<PASSALL>
best-fit memory allocation
<->
The following algorithm can be described as ____.
1 Initialize memory_block(0) = 99999
2 Compute initial_memory_waste = memory_block(0) – job_size
3 Initialize subscript = 0
4 Set counter to 1
5 Do while counter <= number of blocks in memory
If job_size > memory_size(counter)
Then counter = counter + 1
Else
memory_waste = memory_size(counter) – job_size
If initial_memory_waste > memory_waste
Then subscript = counter
initial_memory_waste = memory_waste
counter = counter + 1
End do
6 If subscript = 0
Then put job in waiting queue
Else
Load job into memory_size(subscript)
adjust free/busy memory lists
7 Go fetch next job
<PASSALL>
To access a location in memory when using segmented memory management,
the address is composed of two entries: ____.
<->the segment number and the displacement
<PASSALL>
Assume that four page frames are available and are numbered 1-4. 
Pages A-D have been loaded into page frames 1-4 in order. 
The program has accessed the pages in the following order: B, D, A, C. 
Assume that page E is requested. The ____ page frame will be loaded when the LRU algorithm is used.
<->2
<PASSALL>
first-fit memory allocation
<->
The following algorithm can be described as ____.
1 Set counter to 1
2 Do while counter <= number of blocks in memory
If job_size > memory_size(counter)
Then counter = counter + 1
Else
load job into memory_size(counter)
adjust free/busy memory lists
go to step 4
End do
3 Put job in waiting queue
4 Go fetch next job
<PASSALL>
The primary advantage of storing programs in noncontiguous locations is that ____.
<->main memory is used more efficiently
<PASSALL>
Which of these statements about Memory Manager are true?
<->
allocate and release areas of main memory to processes
coordinate how the different types of memory are used
manage swapping between main memory and disk, when main memory is to small to hold all the processes
keeps track of which part of memory are in use and which are not.
<PASSALL>
One of the most important innovations of demand paging was that it made ____ feasible.
<->virtual memory
<PASSALL>
During the second generation, programmers started dividing their 
programs into sections that resembled working sets, really segments, 
originally called roll in/roll out and now is called ____.
<->overlays
<PASSALL>
The following,____, describes the first memory allocation scheme.
<->
Each program to be processed was loaded in its entirety into 
memory and allocated as much contiguous space in memory as it needed
<PASSALL>
With demand paging, jobs are divided into equally sized ____ 
that initially reside in secondary storage.
<->pages
<PASSALL>
____ gives users the appearance that their 
programs are being completely loaded in main memory during their entire processing time.
<->Virtual memory