Which of these statements about files are true?<->
File is a collection of related information
File includes block special files and character special files
File is an abstraction of data stored on HDD
<PASSALL>
Real-time system has ___ and ____ real-time system types<->
hard , soft
<PASSALL>
Allow multiple remote users to run jobs on the computer at once
<->
time sharing systems
<PASSALL>
Which of these statements about address space are true?
<->
Address space is decoupled from the physical memory
Address space is the abstraction that is referenced to the set of addresses a process
<PASSALL>
Which OS can provide many services as print, file, Web, email, ect?
<->
Server OS
<PASSALL>
Server OS serves multiple users at once over a network and allow the users to share ___ and _____ resources
<->
hardware, software
<PASSALL>
____ offers 3 kinds of services: batch, transaction processing, timesharing
<->
Mainframe OS
<PASSALL>
Which of these statements about processes are true?
<->
Associated with each process is set of resources such as executable code, data, stack, CPU registers value, and other information needing to run a program
Process table stores all the information of processes
A program in execution
<PASSALL>
_____ process routine job without interactive user present
<->
batch systems
<PASSALL>
Embedded OS is located in _______
<->
ROM
<PASSALL>
____ runs on systems that have many CPUs (multi-processors, multi-cores, multi-chips)
<->
Multiprocessor OS
<PASSALL>
____ systems are used in time-critical environments where reliability is key and data must be processed within a strict time limit.
<->
Real-time
<PASSALL>
Symbian, Palm, Windows Mobile, Windows CE are ______
<->
Handheld OS
<PASSALL>
_____ serves multiple users at once over a network and allow the users to share hardware and software resources
<->
Server OS
<PASSALL>
_____ supports with dozens of programs started up at the boot time
<->
Multi-programming
<PASSALL>
Handling large numbers of small requests
<->
real-time systems
<PASSALL>
Allow multiple remote users to run jobs on the computer at once
<->
time sharing systems
<PASSALL>
Which of these statements about processes are true?
<->
Process table stores all the information of processes
Associated with each process is set of resources such as executable code, data, stack, CPU registers value, and other information needing to run a program
<PASSALL>
OS goals<->
Execute user programs (mostly for ease of use with performance)
Make the hardware efficiently and convenient to use
Controls and coordinates the use of hardware among the various application programs for various users
Hides the peculiarities (sự khác biệt) of  hardware accessing such as disk or I/O device reading/writing.
<PASSALL>
Von neumann Instruction<->
Instruction cycle: Fetch-Decode-Execute 
Instructions and data are stored in main memory 
Instruction execution carried out by central processing unit (CPU)
<PASSALL>
Mainframe<->
- Are heavily oriented toward processing many jobs at once, 
most of which need prodigious (phi thường) amounts of I/O.
<PASSALL>
Server OS<->
- Serves multiple users at once over a network and allow the users to share hardware and software resources
- Servers can assume particular task on different server (machine) as web, mail, 
application, file, firewall, CA – Certificated authentication, etc …
<PASSALL>
MultipleProcessor OS<->
Is known parallel systems
Runs on systems that have many CPUs (multi-processors, multi-cores, multi-chips)
Many processors communicate in close, share the computer bus, the clock, and sometimes memory and peripheral devices
<PASSALL>
Sensor node OS<->
Sensor nodes are small battery-powered computers with build-in radios. 
They communicate with each other and with a base station using wireless communication.  
Each sensor node is a real tiny computer with CPU, RAM, ROM, and one or more environmental sensors
->Small size, using low power
<PASSALL>
Real-time<->
Hard real-time systems: They provides absolute guarantee certain time.
Soft real-time systems: They can miss deadline (that does not cause permanent damage)
<PASSALL>
Process table<->
Process table (array or linked list) stores all the information of processes 
A system consists of a collection of processes (many programs)
Based on this table, OS switches the CPU between processes
<PASSALL>
Address Space<->
Set of address values which can be accessed by a process.
Each process has it’s own address space.
An instruction of this process can not access an address of another (protection mechanism).
Make the different programs think they have the hardware on their own (protection mechanism).
Address space can be splitted into some decoupled (tách riêng) pages/segments. 
Each byte in a part is numbered from 0 to it’s maximum. Page/segment sizes can be various (larger or smaller).
<PASSALL>
Protection<->
It ensures that all access to system resources is controlled.
Protect the code of OS against the processes  Code of shell can not access address space of OS.
Protect one process against other processes  Code of a process can not access address space of others.
<PASSALL>
Shell<->
It is a piece of software (it is not a part of OS)that essentially provides 
a kind of interface for end-users to access the computer resource.
2 Types of shells:
Command intepreter. Command line interface/ Graphical user interface (GUI)
<PASSALL>
OS Structure<->
Monolithic Systems – Hệ nguyên khối
Layered Systems – Hệ phân lớp
Micro Kernels – Hệ vi nhân
Client-Server Model
Virtual Machines: Máy ảo
Exokernels: Trình quản lý tài nguyên trong hệ thống nhiều máy ảo. 