A ____ is created when a user opens an account to access the computer system.
<->subdirectory
<PASSALL>
When using random access files, the program used to store 
the data follows a set of instructions, called a ____ algorithm, 
that transforms each key into a number, the record’s logical address.
<->hashing
<PASSALL>
The file’s type includes ______
<->Regular, Directories, Character Special, Block Special
<PASSALL>
Which of these statements about the Linked List Allocation are true?
<->
First word of each block is used as pointer to the next one and the rest of the block is for data
Random access is extremely slow
The amount of data storage in a block is not a power of two because the pointer takes up a few bytes
<PASSALL>
The file’s structure includes _______
<->unstructured sequence of bytes, record sequence, tree
<PASSALL>
Many computer users and some operating systems call subdirectories as ____.
<->folders
<PASSALL>
The primary disadvantage of contiguous storage is that ____.
<->file can’t be expanded unless there is empty space available immediately following it
<PASSALL>
A UNIX or Linux system might identify a file as: 
/usr/imfst/flynn/inventory.doc. What represents the root directory is ____.
<->/
<PASSALL>
____ are special files with listings of filenames and their attributes.
<->Directories
<PASSALL>
A ____ is a group of related records that contains information to be used by 
specific application programs to generate reports.
<->file
<PASSALL>
On magnetic disks, files can be organized in one of three ways; ____.
<->sequential, direct, or indexed sequential
<PASSALL>
The `1^(st)` block in each partition is called ______
<->boot block
<PASSALL>
The File Manager is in charge of the system’s ____ components.
<->physical
<PASSALL>
The purpose of an extension is to ____.
<-> identify the type of file
<PASSALL>
_____ are having one directory containing all files
<->Single-Level Directory Systems
<PASSALL>
The file system’s functions are _____
<->
Providing the users a uniform logical view of the information stored on these devices
Hiding the complexity of storage hardware devices
<PASSALL>
The requirements for long-term information storage are _______
<->
It must be possible to store a very large amount of address
The information must be survived the termination of process using it
<PASSALL>
As long as users refer to files in the ____ directory, they can access 
their files without entering the complete name from the highest level to the lowest.
<->working
<PASSALL>
____ allocation allows files to use any storage space available on the disk.
<->Noncontiguous storage
<PASSALL>
1. MBR locates the active partition, reads in its boot block and executes it
2. The computer is booted, the BIOS reads in and executes the MBR
3. The program in boot block loads the OS contained in that partition
Mechanism of booted computer is
<->
None of others